# MICHAEL ORSINI

# GAME DESIGNER

orsinimichael96@gmail.com



https://iammichaelorsini.wordpress.com/



Nettuno, RM

#### **PROFILE**

A calm, analytical, systematic, and detail-oriented Game Designer accustomed to working in agile environments who combines design, programming, and project management skills to craft player-oriented experiences and get the best out of my work and teammates.

.....

### SKILLS

# **Game Engines**

- . Unity Proficient
  - · Create prototypes and games from scratch
  - o Create intermediate C# scripts
  - o Know 2D and 3D tools (physics, raycasts, tilemaps, cinemachine),
  - Create builds.
- . Unreal Proficient
  - Create prototypes and games from scratch
  - o Comprehend C++ scripts and create simple BPs
  - Create materials
  - Know engine tools
  - Create builds.
- Godot Learning Stage
  - Create prototypes and simple games from scratch
  - Create simple scripts in GScript
  - Know the engine and nodes
  - o Create builds.

## **Documentation**

- Proficient in all forms of game design documentation: analysis, pitches, concepts, reports, and GDDs.
- Accustomed to: Confluence, Office suite, and Google suite.

## **Team and Soft skills**

- · Accustomed to agile management ceremonies and best practices.
- Able to use team management software like Jira, Miro, and Trello.
- Most relevant soft skills: Problem-solving, Creativity, Leadership, Conflict Resolution, Adaptability, Proactivity.

## Languages

Italian: Native SpeakerEnglish: Professional

# EDUCATION

## **BSc Computer Science**

La Sapienza

2018 - 2023

- Programming fundamentals: OOP, Databases, Software Engineering
- Game Design basics (Game Design exam)

# **Game Design Course**

DBGA - Online Blended

2023 - 2024

- Design and Game Design fundamentals
- Level Design: theory, white-boxing, mockups
- Narrative Design: theory, worldbuilding, Inky, Twine
- Documentation: all forms of game design documentation
- Agile best practices, industry standards, production cycle

### HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

- Videogames and tabletop games especially RPGs, strategic games
- Brew decks in Magic but I like all TCGs
- Manga and anime lover
- Singing and playing the piano
- Hiking
- · "Gym rat"
- Plant lovers, I like to make terrariums in glass jars

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Game Designer | DGBA

2023 - 2024

I worked on team and personal projects, increasing my design knowledge, documentation, and practical skills.

In the two team projects my dedication, knowledge, and proactivity allowed me to earn my team's trust and hold positions as project manager and lead designer.

#### The Shattered Peak

Jun 2024 - Oct 2024

Survival game developed in Unreal following videogame production cycle with a team of 10 people.

- Lead Designer and Vision Holder:
  - Supervised design choices and game's direction keeping constant communication with every member of the team both individually and with organized meetings;
  - Created documentation and presentations to align the team on the design choices;
  - Organized various test rounds to collect feedback to design and develop the game based on players' feedback as much as possible;
  - Designed a linear game progression with the team through items and collectibles;
  - Created game areas from scratch in UE using landscape and foliage procedural generation tools;
  - Worked on SFX for the game and music for the trailer with Audacity;
  - Created the studio and the game logo with GIMP;
  - Designed the game menus and UI;
  - Captured game clips and edited them to create the game trailer with Unreal and OBS;
  - Layed down the structure, supervised, and worked with the team to fill in the GDD on Confluence.
- Project Manager:
  - Created task backlogs using various software and kept task management environments clean;
  - o Kept communication with stakeholders through weekly reports.

#### **FurCity Survival**

Mar 2024 - May 2024

Hypercasual game developed in Unity following videogame production cycle with a team of 6 people.

- Lead Designer:
  - Supervised design choices and direction of the game keeping constant communication with every member of the team both individually and with organized meetings;
  - Created the hexagon-based game map in Unity;
  - Designed some SFX for the game and music in Audacity;
  - o Designed menu flow;
  - Layed down the structure, supervised, and filled in the GDD with the team on Google Docs.

## **Nuts & Bolty**

Mar 2024 - May 2024

Puzzle platformer developed in solo from scratch in Unity managing all of its parts from Ideation to Vertical Slice.

# IT Consultant | Key Partner

2021 - 2022

I worked in a highly Agile environment as a system integration consultant. This position allowed me to communicate with various teams (front end, marketing, product management), and learn SCRUM and enterprise ceremonies, best practices, and teamwork soft skills.

- TIBCO ActiveMatrix BuisnessWork.
- Splunk.
- SCRUM and enterprise best practices.